RAYMOND HIGHSMITH

San Francisco Bay Area, CA

highsmith.ray@gmail.com

415-633-6073

Raymond Highsmith is looking to apply his experience in healthcare and information technology. He has +14 years of work experience, with several years of tenure in project management, technical analysis and administration of data and migrations.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer



WORK EXPERIENCE

Network System Deployment Coordinator

VMware - Palo Alto, CA 2019 to Present

- Resolve technical issues with 80% Mac and 20% Windows system
- Image Mac system and deploy
- Imaging of shoot Mac and Windows Servers and desktops
- Enter the systems into hardware asset management software
- Track and resolve tickets with ticket management systems

Information Technology Team Lead

EMR CPR

2019 to Present

Location, Fremont CA

- Migrate desktop workstations
- Configure workstations and servers
- Q.A. system installations and configurations
- Lead teams during various relocation projects

Biomechanical and Technology Specialist

Life Chiropractic College West - Hayward, CA

2015 to Present

- State of the art diagnostic equipment specialist
- Project Manager- Computer Technician- Service Representative
- Outreach coordination with local businesses- Data analysis

Director of Operations

Arbor Vitae Labs - San Francisco Bay Area, CA 2011 to 2014

- Monitor and develop laboratory standards and procedures to attempt GLP standards and OCED principles.- Development of partnerships with companies in the development of products.
- Maintain and monitor testing, produce recommendations and patent new discoveries.- Supervise research in developing applications for LED light monitoring.

Project Specialist

Kessil Lighting - Richmond, CA

2010 to 2011

- Created and developed new projects and refine laboratory conditions for research using their L.E.D. lights for multiple conditions and platforms.
- Intricate team member in creating and maintain databases of experimental data.
- Consulted with engineers on the configuration of light composition.
- Implemented breeding protocols.
- Sales department Consultant

Undergraduate Research Assistant and Computer Lab Technician

USDA-ARS - Albany, CA

2008 to 2009

- Integrated biological technologies to test genetic experiments.
- Responsible for genetic profiling using P.C.R. methods.
- Mapped genetic changes to phenotype characteristics in mutant plants.
- Prepare chemical formulas using dilution calculation and protocols using proper handling and storage of volatile and toxic chemicals as per specifications.
- Apply data analysis to databases.

Senior Desktop Support Technician

College of the Canyons

2006 to 2007

- Administered workstations and associated network equipment and devices.
- Implement security measures. Improve network and desktop performance and security through beta testing.
- Consultations on possible network expansion or upgrades based on current network architecture.
- Provide technical support and emergency repairs to hardware and software issues.
- Catalog, install and maintain biology-related applications and services.

Network System Consultant

College of the Canyons

2006 to 2007

- Consulted various professionals on biotechnology concepts and techniques.
- Provided documentation and integration methods.
- Standardized class methods to interactive learning on the internet.

Network Technician L2

College of the Canyons

2005 to 2005

- 2005
- Consulted users with technical support for hardware & software issues.
- Perform routine maintenance, installation, and troubleshooting of MAC and PC systems.- Implemented advisement and recommendation of customer support software system.
- Provided departmental services to increase efficiency, reduce down times, and streamline communications for provided resolutions.

Desktop and Backup Administrator

AIDS Healthcare Foundation

2001 to 2004

Supervised installation of services in various locations throughout the United States.- Consulted recommendations to implement policies to maintain HIPPA compliance of patient data files. - Managed multiple backups of company data at various facilities on and offsite. - Maintained patients' databases and 24/7 support.- Negotiated sales, installed and configured servers network equipment. - Supervised installations of internet along with configuration and implementation of security measures. - Improved network and desktop performance and security.- Administered wireless access to Smartphone's, PDA's, tablet PC's, computers and printers and any other device requested.

Lead Network Technician

Buchalter, Nemer, Fields & Younger 1997 to 2000

Greater Los Angeles Area

- Created training programs for employees on network systems and procedures.
- Managed and maintained network group policies, local policies on servers,
- Administered windows workstation images.- Performed routine data backup and off-site and cloud storage
- Optimized research lab beta testing.
- Sustained PBX and IP phone systems as well as BYOD.



EDUCATION

Doctor of Chiropractic in Chiropractic

Life Chiropractic College West 2014 to 2019

Bachelor of Applied Science in (B.A.Sc.), Genetics and Plant Biology

University of California, Berkeley - Berkeley, CA 2007 to 2010

Associate of Arts and Sciences in (A.A.S.), Human Biology

College of the Canyons 2005 to 2007

Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator

Mount Sierra College 2004 to 2005

Associate of Arts in (A.A.), Computer Aided Drafting and Design

ITT Technical Institute 1992 to 1994



SKILLS

• Genetics Software Documentation Research

 LINKS	
(e)	

http://www.linkedin.com/in/raymond-highsmith-503a117